Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection 1790-2022 PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Political Posters, 1840-2008; 100 item(s) (approximately)
  - Subseries V.2 State and Local Elections, 1856-1958
    - Republican Candidates on State Ticket, 1936 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Poster issued by Thomas F. Barry, Director, Publicity Division, Republican State Committee. The candidates (each with a sketch) are as follows: Justice William F. Bleakley (Gov.), Col. Ralph K. Robertson (Lt. Gov.), John A. May (Comp.), James P. Hill (Assoc. judge), Natalie Couch (Con.-at- Large), Anthony J. Contiguglia (Con.-at-Large), and Nathan D. Perlman (Atty. Gen.). On back, "Gift of Mrs. Geo. Wilde. Nov. 19, 1936.
    - "Re-elect John J. O'Connor to Congress (16th Dist.)" Banner, 1938 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Banner with a gromet in each corner was printed by All Around Equipment and Novelty Co., with a union printing label. On back, H.B. Hoffman. Nov. 15, 1938.
    - Sheriff of Monmouth County Proclamation to prevent and punish bribery at Primaries, Conventions, and Elections, 1938 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Howard Height was Sheriff. Acquisition date(?) on front, "EB Child/39".
    - "Douglas Mathewson (Fusion) for Borough President (Bronx)", 1913 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Poster has a union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Slogan was: "A Vote for Mathewson Is a Vote to Keep the TIGER Out of Borough Hall". On back, "Rec'd Mar. 12, 1945".
    - "Vote American...Republican. William J. McDonough [for Assemblyman]", 1940 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Poster has a union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 7 1940.
    - "Re-Elect Caroline O'Day...For Representative-at-Large...", 1940 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has a union printing label 12 and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Slogan was: "Make a Representative Woman Your Representative!" Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct 22 1940.
    - "Elect John J. McNaboe and Al. Smith, Jr. for Delegates...", 1940 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Banner printed by Artco Banner Co. and stamped with a Sign and Pictorial Union Label. On back, "Was on Lamp post at S.E. corner of First Ave and E. 52d St. Tue Apr. 2, 1940". Acquisition date(?) on back, Apr. 3, 1940.
    - "For Congress...Kenneth F. Simpson...", 1940 (Folder FF 05-22)
      The small card has a union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. On the back of card is a map of the 17th Congressional District.
    - "William T. Pheiffer for Congress...", 1940 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has union printing label 118 and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 7 1940.
    - "Look Them in the Eyes...Tell them...", c.1940 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Poster based on a pamphlet of the Southern Conference for Human Welfare, Religious Associates of the National Citizens Political Action Committee, NY. Poster features an image of young, black children and the complete statement on the poster is as follows: "Look them in the Eyes...Tell them they are "second rate" Americans, Tell them they aren't entitled to a real education, Tell them they can't have decent homes, Go AHEAD, tell them, IF YOU CAN, but DON'T LET AN AMERICAN HEAR YOU". Acquisition date(?) on back, Sept. 3, 1946.
    - "Your Number One Choice for City Council...George S. Counts", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      2 copies. Poster has a union printing label and features a three-quarters face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back of both copies, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Your Number One Choice...Jacob Rosenberg for City Council", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Banner has a printing label -- L.U. 230. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Elect Samuel Null Justice of Supreme Court", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Banner has union printing label 258. On back, "77th Broadway". Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Samuel Null for Justice of the Supreme Court", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has a union printing label 400 and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Re-Elect Sheriff New York County...Daniel E. Finn, Jr....", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has a union printing label 249 and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Democrats! Vote United City Party...", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Banner has union printing label 258. Henry Morgenthau, Sr., Chairman, James G. McDonald, Chair Exec. Comm., David Schenker, Campaign Manager, for United City Party. Acquisition date(?) on front, 11/5/41. On back, "Obtained from Sound Truck parking in front of Stock Exchange Broad St....Nov. 3, 1941".
    - "LaGuardia -- McGoldrick -- Morris", 1941 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has union printing label 363. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "The Public Record of Attorney General John J. Bennett, Jr.", 1942 (Folder FF 05-22)
      The poster was sponsored and paid for by Friends of Attorney General John J. Bennett, Jr. -- Henry Epstein, Solicitor General State of New York, Chairman. The poster is a reprint of a New York Times article publised on July 13, 1942. Acquisition date(?) on back, Mar. 8, 1943.
    - "Defeat O'Leary (Comptroller)...Labor's Enemy...", 1942 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster sponsored by Joint Committee New York State Allied Printing Trade Council -- Printing Trade Council of Greater New York. Acquisition date(?) on back, Mar. 8, 1943.
    - "Vote Row C...American Labor Party", 1942 (Folder FF 05-22)
      2 copies. Acquisition date(?) on back of copy 1, Nov. 4, 1941.
    - "Elect Edgar Nathan, Jr....Borough President (Manhattan)", 1942 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster published by Tenny Press, N.Y.C., with a union printing label. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - "Elect Burton B. Turkus County Judge", 1942 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster features a reprint of a letter of support from Mayor LaGuardia and has a union printing label. Acquisition date(?) on back, March 8, 1943.
    - "Re-Elect John L. Buckley...State Senator", 1942 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. At bottom, "Buy U.S. War Bonds and Stamps". Acquisition date(?) on back, Mar. 8, 1943.
    - "You Can Register NOW! [to vote]", 1944 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Notice features a political caricature signed by Ed Hughes depicting a carful of people heading toward the Board of Elections.
    - "CIO Political Action Committee...Register [to vote]", 1944 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster "Litho in U.S.A." with union printing label. The bold image of an arm with rolled up sleeve holding ballot was drawn by Ben Shahn. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 1, 1944.
    - "Elect Thomas J. Curran...United States Senator...", 1944 (Folder FF 05-21)
      2 copies. At bottom of poster: "Paid Political Advertising" with a union printing label. Acquisition date(?) on back of both copies, Nov. 18, 1944.
    - "Re-Elect Robert F. Wagner United States Senator...", 1944 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has union printing label and features full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on front, Nov. 1, 1944.
    - "Vote for Judge Frankenthaler for the Supreme Court...", 1944 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster published by Tenny Press, N.Y.C. and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 30, 1944.
    - Liberal Party Rally, 1944 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has a union printing label 248. The Rally at Woodbridge High Auditorium was to hear Dean Alfange, August W. Bennet (Candidate for Congress to defeat Ham Fish), and Pierre Denio (Candidate for State Senate). Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 30, 1944.
    - "Re-Elect Edward R. Koch for Justice of the Supreme Court...", c.1947 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster published by Wm. T. Wager, Bronx, NY. with union printing label.
    - "KEEP on the Course...Re-elect Governor Bradford (MA) ...", 1948 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Poster printed by Jerome Press, with a union printing label, and issued by James E. Healy, Concord, Mass. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 9, 1948.
    - "Marcantonio (U.S. Representative, American Labor Party) Fights For You", 1948 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Poster published by The Workshop of Graphic Art with a union printing labor. An interesting graphic poster with an ombre style and a floating head of Marcantonio featured with the head of Roosevelt and two other politicians' heads in the background. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 10 1948.
    - "Dewey-Warren Victory Rally" program, 1948 (Folder FF 05-22)
      The New York Republican County Committee sponsored the victory rally at Madison Square Garden. The Rally included speeches and several songs for everyone to sing. The photographs in the program were courtesy of Greystone Studio. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 10 1948.
    - "Don't Gamble with Machine Government! Newbold Morris...Mayor", 1949 (Folder FF 05-21)
      2 copies. Poster has a union printing label and was issued by the Campaign Committee for the Election of Morris, Uviller (Comptroller), Diserio (Pres. City Council). Features a slot machine on an orange and black background. Acquisition date(?) on back of both copies, Nov 9 1949.
    - "get back to good government! elect Newbold Morris mayor...", 1949 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster sponsored by campaign committee for the election of Morris, Uviller (comptroller), Diserio (pres. of city council) and states: "Paid Political Advt", with union printing label. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 9 1949.
    - "Herbert H. Lehman for U.S. Senator", 1949 (Folder FF 05-21)
      3 copies. Poster published by Parish Press, Inc. with a union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back of all copies, Nov 10 1949.
    - "Vote Republican - Row A...United States Senator...Dulles...Assoc. Judge...Bromley", 1949 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster sponsored by N.Y. State Republican Committee and copyrighted by P. Hallsman and Greystone Studios. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 10 1949.
    - "Vote Today! Vote Row A ...All The Way...", 1951 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has a union printing label and was sponsored by New York Republican County Committee. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 7 1951.
    - "North--South--East--West...All Agree Barkley Best", 1952 (Folder FF 05-22)
      Poster has union printing label 188. Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct. 9 1952.
    - "Don't be left out...Register Now!", 1952 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has seals for The American Heritage Foundation and The Advertising Council. Acquisition date(?) on back, Sep 8 1952.
    - "Re-Elect Ives U.S. Senator...", 1952 (Folder FF 05-23)
      3 copies. Poster published by New York Republican State Committee and has a union printing label. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back of all copies, Nov. 4, 1952.
    - Re-Elect Thomas C. Desmond for State Senator, 1952 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has a union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, November 4, 1952.
    - City-Wide Rally To Stop Anti-Negro Genocide, 1952 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Rally was produced under the auspices of National Civil Rights Congress and the Harlem Civil Rights Congress. The Rally was in response to the lynchiing death of Willie McGee.
    - "Stop Tammany...Elect the Independent ticket Halley - Mellen - Canudo...", 1953 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster is a Paid Political Advertisement -- paid for by the Citizen's Committee for the Election of Halley-Mellen-Canudo. Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct 27 1953.
    - "Smash boss rule! Elect Halley Mayor...", 1953 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster is a Paid Political Advertisement -- paid for by the Citizen's Committee for the Election of Halley-Mellen-Canudo. Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct 21 1953.
    - "For Clean Government, Elect Halley Mayor", 1953 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has a union printing label and photographic image of candidate signed by photographer, Victor Keppler. Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct 21 1953.
    - "For Lieut. Governor...Raymond McGovern", 1954 (Folder FF 05-21)
      Poster published by N.Y. State Republican Committee and has a union printing label. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 19 1954.
    - Send Mac (Senator MacNeil Mitchell) Back!, 1954 (Folder FF 05-23)
    - "MacNeil Mitchell is your State Senator...", 1954 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has a union printing label 168 and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 19 1954.
    - Elect Vincent A. Lupiano for Justice of the Supreme Court, 1954 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has a union printing label 285 and features a full-face portrait image of candidate on which someone drew a mustache. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 19 1954.
    - Elect Francis X. Conlon for Justice of the Supreme Court, 1954 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster published by Criterion Press, Inc. and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov 19 1954.
    - Poster for Treasure House New York State Exhibition, 1954 (Folder FF 05-23)
      The exhibition was held at the Roberson Memorial Center in Binghamton and featured objects from prehistoric times to present. Acquisition date(?) on back, Dec 2 1954.
    - "Elect Justice Maxwell Shapiro...Judge of the Court of General Sessions...", 1956 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster published by Tenny Press, N.Y.C. and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on front, November 5, 1956
    - "Send Jacob K. Javits to U.S. Senate...", 1956 (Folder FF 05-23)
    - Bentley Kassal (Democratic-Liberal) for Assembly, 1956 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster published by The Criterion Press, Inc. and features full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on front, November 5, 1956.
    - Elect Alice Sachs...New York State Assembly, 1956 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster has a union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on front, November 5, 1956. A letter from Kathleen H. Mortimer is attacched on the back in support of Sachs' candidacy.
    - "U.S. Senator Dulles...Vote Row A", c.1958 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Poster sponsored by the N.Y. State Republican Committee and image of Dulles copyrighted by P. Hallsman.
    - Ferber For Sheriff bumper sticker, c.1950s (Folder FF 05-23)
    - Re-Elect Senator Case bumper sticker, c.1950s (Folder FF 05-23)
    - "Join the fight...vote reform...defeat Tammany Bossism...Ryan (Congress) and Ohrenstein (State Senate), c.1960 (Folder FF 05-23)
      Pamphlet urging citizens to vote in the Primary for the Reform Candidates, Ryan and Ohrenstein.
    - Re-Elect Congressman "Bill" Widnall bumper sticker, c.1950s (Folder FF 05-23)
      Bumper sticker made by EZY-OFF BANNER and promises it is easy to remove.
- Series VI. Motion Picture and Theater Posters, 1790-2022
  This series includes posters advertising individual plays operettas, mistrel shows, musicians, specialty acts, and dance companies, as well as posters advertising motion pictures.
  The bulk of the series dates from the late nineteenth to the early twentieth century. This includes text playbills that provide a detailed record of performances in NYC from the 1790s to 1890s.
  - Subseries VI.A Motion Picture Posters, 1914-2022
    This subseries contains posters created to advertise movies. Some posters are by identified artists or printmakers, such as Strobridge Litho. Co.
    - "Priscilla about to be put in the Stocks for Witchcraft" from 'When Broadway was a Trail', a Shubert Feature, 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Advertisement produced by World Film Corporation of New York City.
    - "Trial of Henry Minnet" from 'When Broadway was a Trail', a Shubert Feature, 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Ad produced by World Film Corporation of New York City.
    - "In the Land of the Head Hunters", 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features Native Kwakwaka'wakw men (from British Columbia) in their masks and carvings. Edward Curtis was a noted photographer, and he produced this documentary featuring Native North Americans.
    - "Overcome by the Drug" from 'The Mystery of Edwin Drood', 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Features Tom Terriss in leading role on bed overcome by opium.
    - "Like an Avenging Spirit Jasper is Always Near" from 'The Mystery of Edwin Drood', 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Features a couple in a garden with a gentleman in the background.
    - "The Kangaroo, Terrors of Old New Orleans", 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Poster features four scenes from the film: "Adrian Starts on his Trip of Inspection", "On Board the Barge", "The Discovery of the Tell-Tale Book", and "Buck Flint Unaided Attempts Dick Hullum's Arrest". The film was based on stories by Harris Dickson.
    - "Miss Betty Nansen, the Distinguished Emotional Actress Featured by The Great Northern Film Co. in 'The Fallen Idol'", 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The poster was produced by Acme Lith. Co. The film was a William Fox Features, Box Office Attraction Film Rental Company of New York City. The large poster features an image of Betty Nansen wearing a feathered hat, pearls and two medals.
    - "A Jolly Party" from 'The Price of Treachery', 1914 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Features a scene with a group at a table outside with one playing the accordian.
    - Howard Estabrook in "M'Liss" with Barbara Tennant, 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features a crowd around a man and a donkey. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a Shubert Feature.
    - Clara Kimball Young in "The Heart of the Blue Ridge", 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by World Film Corporation of New York City (Lewis J. Selznick was president and general manager). "The Heart of the Blue Ridge" was a Shubert feature.
    - Clara Kimball Young in "The Deep Purple", 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City and features an interior scene with Clara Kimball Young and Milton Sills. The film was based on a 1910 play written by Paul Armstrong and was an A. Liebler Feature.
    - Beatriz Michelena in "The Lily of Poverty Flat", 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features men gambling around a small table. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a California Motion Picture Corporation feature.
    - Beatriz Michelena in "The Lily of Poverty Flat", 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features "Lily" in an interior space with a couple folding an American flag. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a California Motion Picture Corporation feature.
    - Beatriz Michelena in "The Lily of Poverty Flat", 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features two men panning for gold. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a California Motion Picture Corporation feature.
    - Lillian Russell in "Wildfire", a Shubert Feature, 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features Lillian Russell and Lionel Barrymore in an interior space. The film was produced by the Shuberts based on a 1908 broadway play, Wildfire, by George V. Hobart and George Broadhurst.
    - Lillian Russell in "Wildfire", a Shubert Feature, 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features Lillian Russell in an interior space. The film was produced by the Shuberts based on a 1908 broadway play, Wildfire, by George V. Hobart and George Broadhurst.
    - "What Happened to Jones" with Fred Mace, William A. Brady Picture Plays, Inc., 1915 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Features Fred Mace with two gentlemen near a dressing table. The film was based on a 1897 play by George Broadhurst of the same title.
    - "The Ballet Girl," William A. Brady Picture Plays, Inc., 1916 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Features Alice Brady in the leading role in a bedroom scene with a man. The film was based on a novel, Carnival, by Compton MacKenzie.
    - "Equitable Motion Picture Corp. Presents Robert T. Haines in 'Human Cargoes'", 1916 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Still produced by Equitable Motion Picture Corp. (founded by Arthur Spiegel of Chicago) and features a group examining a young woman.
    - "Grand Central Palace Hero Land", circa 1917 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      J. Carl Mueller designed the still, and Heywood Strasser & Voight Litho. Co. N.Y. published the still. Hero Land promised "The greatest spectacle the world has ever seen for the greatest need the world has ever known. British tank 'Britannia' in action".
    - "Sincerely Douglas Fairbanks", circa 1920 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Poster features a smiling Douglas Fairbanks looking over a wall of some sort.
    - Mary Pickford in "Through the Back Door", 1921 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Poster features an image of Mary Pickford sitting on her bed holding a doll. The movie was directed by Jack Pickford and Alfred Green with scenario by Marion Fairfax.
    - Douglas Fairbanks in "The Nut", 1921 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Poster features a scene with Douglas Fairbanks and Marguerite De La Motte in evening dress.
    - "Danse Macabre", 1922 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      Information about the still handwritten on back: "Adolph Bolm with Ruth Page (his pupil) Olin Howland as Death in Adolph Bolm screen version of the Dance Macabre, music by C. Saint-Saens. A-2"
    - "Danse Macabre", 1922 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      Written on back: "Adolph Bolm with Ruth Page (his pupil) Olin Howland as Death in Adolph Bolm screen version of the Dance Macabre, music by C. Saint-Saens. B-2"
    - "A Woman of Paris: A Drama of Fate", 1923 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Features a dining scene with Edna Purviance and Adolphe Menjou. The film was written, directed, produced and scored by Charles Chaplin.
    - "D.W. Griffith's - 'Isn't Life Wonderful'", 1924 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Features a scene from the film directed and produced by D.W. Griffith, based on a novel by Geoffrey Moss, and starring Carol Dempster and Neil Hamilton.
    - "The Enemy", 1925 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      Information about the still handwritten on back: "John Wray, Fay Bainter and Jane Seymour in 'The Enemy'".
    - "Douglas Fairbanks in 'Don Q, Son of Zorro'", 1925 (Folder FF 06.1-03)
      Features a scene between Douglas Fairbanks and Mary Astor and an image of Douglas Fairbanks in full-swashbuckling regalia superimposed over an edge of the scene.
    - "Tarzan the Tiger", 1929 (Folder FF 06.1-02)
      Advertisement in the shape of an elephant. On the reverse side, "Tarzan the Tiger by Edgar Rice Burroughs with Frank Merrill and Natalie Kingston. New adventures, hazards, thrills. Printed in U.S.A."
    - "William Fox Presents Lightnin' ", 1930 (Folder FF 06.1-01)
      Bottom front of still: "Made in U.S.A."
    - Carl Laemmle presents Harry Langdon and Slim Summerville in "See America Thirst", 1930 (Folder FF 06.1-02)